Guide to the Community Service Society Archives
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XIV, Files, 1939-1960
  - Subseries XIV.1: Files, Alphabetic
    - Health - Nursing (also see in Studies, Internal): (Box 333)
      - Educational Nursing Department, 1939-52 (also see, as later named, Public Health Nursing Service Description Prepared for 100th Anniversary (Box 335)
      - Survey Committee 1948 by Caroline Falls (Box 335)
      - History, Miscellaneous (Box 335)
      - Outline of Historical Data 1948 (Box 335)
      - Educational Nursing Studies 1945-49 (Box 336)
      - Educational Nursing Study by M.L. Shetland 1943 Correspondence (Box 336)
      - Educational Nursing Summary (Camery) 1957 (Box 336)
      - Field Work Contacts (Box 336)
      - Foster Home Supervision, the Nurses' Part in Family Service Project to Place Infants in Foster Homes, 1944-1946 (Box 336)
      - Gross Dental Needs in 324 PHNS Families 1954 (Box 336)
      - Harlem River Tuberculosis Service 1941-44 (Box 336)
      - Health Examination Clinics of D.E.N. 1950 (Box 336)
      - Health Improvement Classes 1944-45 (Box 336)
      - Lenox Hill Health Service, 1943, 1951 (Box 336)
      - Manuals of Practice, 1959, 1954, 1948 (Box 337)
      - Moton Health Service 1939 ff. (Box 337)
      - Public Health Nursing Service (Formerly Educational Nursing Dept.) 1952-60 (Box 337)
      - Publications of D.E.N. and of the P.H.N.S. of Family Services Department, 1943-53. Includes "Guide" samples (Box 337)
      - Recreation 1948 (Box 337)
      - Student Training 1938-42 (Box 337)
      - Time Spent in Direct Service to 89 Families by East River Public Health Nurses 1955 (Box 337)
      - Time Study, PHN Section, 1957 (Box 337)
    - Health: Tuberculosis: (Box 338)
      - Historical Background of TB Family Division, 1843 to Merger 1939 (Box 338)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 338)
      - Otisville Sanatorium (Box 338)
      - Study Committee 1939-42 (Box 338)
      - (TB) Work of AICP and COS, Summary of Study, 1941 (Box 338)
    - Health: Miscellaneous: (Box 339)
      - Asian Flu 1957 (Box 339)
      - Fluoridation, Statement 1957 (Box 339)
      - Goldwater Hospital Project: An Evaluation of the Post-Discharge Needs of Rehabilitated Older Persons, 1959-60 (Box 339)
      - Health Problems of Families Under Care in Family Service Department January 1940 (Box 339)
      - Maternity Service Project (Public Affairs Dept.) 1957-62 (Box 339)
      - New York Hospital: Dr. Webster's Study of Health of Some CSS Families 1940 (Box 339)
      - Program of Health Associate 1951-55 (Box 339)
      - Proposed Health Project with Cornell Medical School, 1954 (Box 339)
    - Historical Data (Miscellaneous) (Box 339)
    - Home Economics and Nutrition:
      - Budget Planning (Box 339)
      - Budgets for Boarding Homes (Box 339)
      - Cost Schedules, 1940-49, Budget Standards for Families (Box 339)
      - Cost Schedule, 1950-60 (Box 339)
      - History, Nutrition Service (Box 340)
      - Home Economics Committee, 1945-47 (Box 340)
      - Home Economics Committee, 1941-44 (Box 340)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 340)
      - Nutrition for Older Persons (Box 340)
      - Nutrition Service (fully described) 1948 (Box 340)
    - Homemaker Service - Advisory Committee, 1946-47, 1948-49:
      - Annual Reports, 1946-60 (Box 341)
      - Extended Homemaker Service Project, 1954-59 (Box 341)
      - Harlem Scholarship Fund, 1948-58 (Box 341)
      - Homemakers Club, 1946-50 (Box 341)
      - Human Interest Case Stories (Box 341)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-56 (Box 341)
      - National Committee, 1949-61 (Box 342)
      - Study Group, 1948 (Box 342)
      - Tenth Anniversary 1956 (Box 342)
    - Housing:
      - Abandoned Buildings (Box 342)
      - Adjusted Rents (Box 342)
      - Airshafts, 1940-41 (Box 342)
      - Cellar Occupancy (Box 342)
      - Cellar Occupancy Photos n.d. (Box 342)
      - City Council Bills with Comments 6/39-6/39; 10/39-10/40 (Box 342)
      - Function and Policy of Committee on Housing, 1941 ff (Box 342)
      - James Weldon Johnson Community Center, 1947-55 (Box 342)
      - Legislative Action by Committee, Miscellaneous, 1939 (Box 343)
      - Legislative Book I Book I; Book II; 1939 (Box 343)
      - Miscellaneous, 1939-42 (Box 343)
      - " - Miscellaneous Activities of AICP (Box 343)
      - " - Miscellaneous: C.O.S. 1938-39 (Box 343)
      - Old Law Tenement Awards, 1939 (Box 343)
      - Photos - Miscellaneous snapshots, negatives, New York City, 1940s (Box 343)
      - Relocation of Residential Site Tenants (Box 343)
      - Reports, Annual 1938 ff., Biennial, 40-year (C.O.S.) 1938 50 year 1948 (Box 344)
      - Service to Families and Individuals, 1936-48 (Box 344)
      - Urban Development, 1956-58: Speeches, statement of Positions (Box 344)
    - Hundred Year Association, Dinners for Howard Rusk 1960 John D. Rockefeller III 1959 Keith McHugh 1958 (Box 344)
    - Hundredth Anniversary Book, "Frontiers in Human Welfare" 1948 see in Reports section:
      - Letters and Memos (Box 344)
      - Program and Publicity Plans (Box 344)
      - Survey and Plan, John Price Jones; Report and Suggestions, Prof, Otto Pollak (Box 345)
      - Symposia Programs, Bulletins (Box 345)
      - Symposium I Papers, "Human Relations in Science and Practice", 1948 (Box 345)
      - Symposium II Papers, "Health and Family Life", 1948 (Box 345)
      - Symposium III Papers "Professional Social Work: Its (Box 345)
      - Substance and World Significance" (Also the 50th anniversary of the N.Y. School of Social Work of Columbia University and the Community Service Society) 1948 (Box 345)
      - Symposium Publications: Book Review N.Y. Times Aug 21, 1949 Columbia University Press: "The Family in a Democratic Society" and "Social Work as Human Relations" (Box 345)
      - Symposium Synopsis: "Guideposts for a Second Century of Community Service", 1948 (Duplicate in Reports Section) (Box 345)
      - Town Hall Meeting 1/22/48 (Box 345)
    - Immigrants (New): Church World Service, Project for the Integration of New Immigrants, 1947, 1954 (Box 346)
    - Immigrants and New Americans Project Serving People from Eastern Europe Located in Chelsea-Lowell District, 1955-60 (Box 346)
    - Immigrants and New Americans 1939-54 (Box 346)
    - Minutes of Welfare Council Committee, 1951-55 (Box 346)
    - Intercommunication, (Staff) Committee on, 1953-54 (Box 346)
    - Inter-professional staff Meetings (in Family Service Dept.) 1951-53 (Box 346)
    - James Weldon Johnson Community Center, Committee Minutes, 1948-49 (Box 347)
    - Jefferson Houses Site Relocation Service - East River District of Family Service 1956-57 (Box 347)
    - Juvenile Delinquency, Miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 347)
    - Kempshall, Anna see; Reorganization, 1951-1952 (Box 347)
    - " "Kingsbury Affair" 1938 (AICP) (Box 347)
    - Library Plan, Catalog Lists, Forms, Staff Committee, 1951-55 (Box 347)
    - Library, Reports 1953-56 (Box 347)
    - Library Advisory (Staff) Committee, Minutes, etc., 1953-63 (Box 347)
    - " Library, of Russell Sage Foundation and CSS, 1912-49 (Box 347)
    - Lobbying for Social Legislation, 1936, 1959 (Box 347)
    - Mailing Samples for Special Events, mainly 1959 (Box 347)
    - Meetings, General Staff, 1953-58 (Box 347)
    - Mental Health: Greenberg Bill to Amend State Medical Practice Act, 1949-54 (Box 348)
    - Mental Health in Family Service, Miscellaneous Papers by Staff, 1950-59 (Box 348)
    - Merger of AICP and COS to Form CSS:
      - Completed: Certificate of Consolidation, 1939 Last Separate Annual Reports, First CSS Annual Report, first Organization Chart, CSS; First Descriptive Brochure, CSS; First List of Officers and Committee Members of CSS (Box 348)
      - Comments from Prominent Persons, from Contributors, et al 1939 (Box 348)
      - Correspondence and Minutes of AICP re: Merger 1938-39 (Box 348)
      - COS Correspondence and Report RE: Merger 1939 (Box 348)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Minutes and Signed Proxies, 1939 (Box 348)
      - First Year After (Box 349)
      - Founders Meeting 10/17/79 (Box 349)
      - Meetings - Administrative Committee & Board 4/39 (Box 349)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 349)
      - Naming the New Society, 1939 (Box 349)
      - News Clippings (Box 349)
      - Photos, 1939 (Box 349)
      - Documents (Box 349)
      - Pre-merger Thinking (Box 349)
    - Minutes - Includes staff committees only if "twinned" with Board Com., like Staff Plan and Scope Committee, other staff committees in straight alphabetical order. Minutes are filed separately at the end of the alphabet: (Box 350)
      - Committees, Miscellaneous, ca. 1940-41 (Box 350)
      - Adopt-A-Family 1939-48; 1949-54; 1955-59 (Box 350)
      - Budget, 1940-55 (Box 350)
      - Budget and Planning, 1956-59 (Box 351)
      - Bureau for Men and Boys, 1939-41; 1942-45; 1946 June, 1950 continued as Youth Bureau (Box 351)
      - Child Care, 1945-50 (Box 351)
    - Minutes (Box 352)
      - Chinatown Health, 1950-61 (Box 352)
      - Contributors, 1942, 1943, 1950 1951-56 (Box 352)
      - District Committees:
        - Bronx 1952-59 (Box 352)
        - Chelsea-Lowell 1942-46; 1947-52 (Box 352)
        - District Committees: (Box 353)
        - Chelsea-Lowell 1953-55, 1956-60 (4 Volumes) (Box 353)
        - East River 1953-56; 1957-59 (A combination of former Yorkville, Mt. Morris, and Jefferson Districts) (2 Volumes) (Box 353)
        - Gramercy 1946-49 (Box 353)
        - Harlem 1942-49 (Box 353)
        - District Committees (Box 354)
        - Harlem 1950-55; 1956-58 (Box 354)
        - Jefferson 1947-52 (Box 354)
        - Jefferson-Yorkville 1952-53 (Box 354)
        - Mt. Morris 1945-46 (Box 354)
        - Queens 1939-48; 1950-60 (Box 354)
        - Queens Subcommittees, 1939-48 (Box 354)
        - District Committees (Box 355)
        - Queens Subcommittees, 1946-51 (Box 355)
        - Riverdale (West Bronx Advisory) 1949-52 (Box 355)
        - Riverside 1944-48; 1949-54; 1955-60 (3 Volumes) (Box 355)
        - Yorkville 1940-43 (Box 355)
      - Yorkville 1944-49; 1950-52 (Box 356)
      - Executive Council 1939-40; 1941-42; 1943-44 (Box 356)
      - Minutes - Family Service (s) 1943-47; 1948-53; 1954-57; 1958-60 (4 Folders) (Box 357)
      - Minutes - Finance 1940-43 (Box 358)
      - Minutes - Finance 1944-46; 1947-51; 1952-59 (Box 358)
      - Health 1943-51 (Box 358)
      - Hospitality 1957 (Box 358)
      - Minutes - Housing 1939-41 (Box 359)
      - Minutes - Housing 1942-49; 1950-54; 1955-57; 1958-60 (5 Volumes) (Box 359)
      - Opportunity Shop 1944-47; 1948-51 (Box 360)
      - Opportunity Shop Board of Managers 1941-59 (Box 360)
      - Opportunity Shop Special Meetings 1941 (Box 360)
      - Personnel Needs 1956-57 (Box 360)
      - Plan and Scope 1949-51 (Board) (Box 360)
      - Plan and Scope 1949-51 (Staff) (Box 360)
    - Minutes of Committees: (Box 361)
      - Public Affairs 1952-55; 1956-59 (Box 361)
      - Public Interest 1942-58 (Box 361)
      - Real Estate 1939-53 (Box 361)
      - Research 1940-43; 1944-45 (Box 362)
      - Research 1946, 1947, 1948, 1949 1950-59 (Box 362)
      - Survey (Hundredth Anniversary) January 1948 - February 1949 (Box 362)
      - Trustees, Board of, and Administrative Com: (Box 363)
      - First Meeting April 12, 1939 (Box 363)
      - May 1939 - March 1940 (Includes Annual Corporate Meeting)
        - April 1940 - December 1940 (Box 363)
        - 1941, 1942, 1943 (Box 364)
        - 1944, 1945, 1946, 1947 (Box 365)
        - 1948, 1949, 1950 (Box 366)
        - 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954 (Box 367)
        - 1955, 1956, 1957, 1958 - October 1959 December, 1959 -December 1960 (Box 368)
      - Tuberculosis Study December 1940 - October 1941 (Box 369)
      - Volunteer Education 1956-57 and November 1960 "Orientation and Education" (Box 369)
      - Volunteer Workroom 1956-57 (Box 369)
      - War Emergency Agencies 1943-46 (Box 369)
      - Women's Committee and/or Council 1939-51 (Box 369)
      - Women's Council Executive 1940-42; 1952-55; 1956-60 (Box 369)
      - Youth Bureau 1950-55 (Box 369)
      - Youth Bureau 1956-60; Subcommittee on Legal Problems 1958 (Box 370)
      - Youth Bureau Executive 1932-40 (Box 370)
      - Youth and Justice 1939-47 (Box 370)
    - Narcotics, 1951 Report by Leonard V. Harrison; 1959 (Box 370)
    - New York Association of Day Nurseries 1948-52 (Box 370)
    - New York City Welfare Department, 1947-50 (Box 370)
    - New York City Welfare Department Allowances, 1949-50 (Box 370)
    - New York City Welfare Department. Report of Mayor's Committee of Inquiry 1959-60 (Box 370)
    - New York City Youth Board: (Box 371)
      - Committee on Child Welfare and Family Services – 1950-1960 (Box 371)
      - Contracts 1952-60 (Box 371)
      - Correspondence Regarding Contracts 1949-1962 (Box 371)
      - Miscellaneous 1950-60 (Box 371)
    - New York Educational Projects, Inc. 1945 (Box 371)
    - N.Y. School of Social Work (Later Columbia University School): (Box 372)
      - Early Classes (photos) (Box 372)
      - Fund Raising (Box 372)
      - General (Box 372)
      - 60th Anniversary Dinner (Box 372)
    - Non-Sectarian (Family) Agencies: Association of Independent Agencies 1947- (Box 372)
    - Non-Sectarian (Family) Agencies - Miscellaneous 1944-51; 1951-55 (Box 373)
    - N.Y. Times Neediest Cases, see Times neediest Cases Appeal (Box 373)
    - Nursing, Dept. see Health (Box 373)
    - Nurses House, Inc. (Formerly Cobble Court Inc.) 1947-48 Minutes, etc. (Box 373)
    - Deeds and other Legal Papers Re; Property in Babylon, L.I. 1924 (AICP) -47 (Box 373)
    - Nutrition See Home Economics and ... (Box 373)
    - Office Space: (Box 373)
    - To Move or Not to Move, etc. 1955-59 (Box 373)
    - Minutes of Special Committee on Housing of Offices 1956-59 (Box 373)
    - Opportunity Shops 1959-60 (Box 373)
    - Optical Membership Plan (for Staff) 1944-57 (Box 373)
    - Organization Charts 1941-58, Actual and Proposed (Box 374)
    - Organizations, Miscellaneous:
      - Citizens' Advice Bureaus in Great Britain, from 1939 (Box 374)
      - Community Chest for New York? 1939 or earlier to 1948 (Box 374)
      - Community Council see Separate Listing: Welfare Council (Box 374)
      - Greater New York Fund see Separate Listing (Box 374)
      - International Conference of Social Work 1956 (re: participation by CSS General Director) (Box 374)
      - Junior League of N.Y.C. 1940-57 (Box 374)
      - Miscellaneous 1940 ff (Box 374)
      - N.Y. Hospital, Collaboration in Dunbar Study of (Box 374)
      - Mental Components of Organic Disease 1938 (C.O.S.) (Box 374)
      - Planned Parenthood 1953-58 (Box 374)
      - Society of St. Johnsland, 1957-58 (Box 374)
      - Survey Associates 1948 (Box 374)
      - United Councils of Greater New York, (proposed) Proposal to United Welfare, Health and Hospital Councils 1946 (Box 374)
    - Participation, Ad Hoc Staff Committee on, 1954-55 (Box 375)
    - Personalities (also see Contributors)
      - Atterbury, Grosvenor, Committee on Housing 1936 (C.O.S.) - 1956 (Box 375)
      - Barnes, Mrs. Courtland D. (Katherine D. Barney, Board Member from 1920 (Box 375)
      - Clark, Stephen C. and Susan V.H. Clark as Donors 1915 ff. (Box 375)
      - Davies Stanley Powell: General Director C.O.S. 1933-39; CSS 1939-57; Associate in Planning 1957-58 (Box 375)
      - DeForest; Robert W. (including Several Photos); Johnston; Story of Cecelia Beau portrait of Robert (Box 375)
      - Ecker, Frederick H. 1923-64 (Box 375)
      - Emerson, Guy, and Mrs. 1935-69 (Box 375)
      - Flagler, Harry Harkness 1933-58 (Box 375)
      - Foster, Austin T. and Mrs. Marjories 1938-58 (Box 375)
      - Gifford, Walter S. (2 Folders): in CSS 1939 ff, in C.O.S. 1928-39 (Box 375)
      - Personalities: (Box 376)
      - Goodrich, Ernest P. - Committee on Housing 1927 (C.O.S.) - 1955 (CSS) (Box 376)
      - Hartley, Robert M. - Descendants of AICP Founder (Box 376)
      - Horner, Frederick C. - Com. on Housing and Former Tenement House Com., CSS and C.O.S. (Box 376)
      - Kirkbride, Franklin 1934.... (Box 376)
      - Leffingwell, Russell C. and Mrs. Lucy Hewitt L. (Box 376)
      - Lowell, Josephine Shaw (1843-1905) a Pamphlet by Margaret Rich 1954 (Box 376)
      - Matthews, William H. - photo and early Bio (His Papers at N.Y. Public Library) (Box 376)
      - McCook, the Hon. Philip J. and Mrs. McCook 1905-63 (Box 376)
      - Merrill, Edwin K. and Edwin 6.-Correspondence 1915 ff (Box 376)
      - Milbank, Albert G. (Box 376)
      - Miscellaneous: Folder I, A-L; Folder II, M-Z (Includes Ms of a Bulletin "Service by Families" by Elsie Kearns for the 100th Anniversary in 1948 also some photos (Box 376)
      - Personalities: (Box 377)
      - Morgan, J.P. and Junius (Box 377)
      - Osborn Mrs. William Henry (Katherine S. Haven Redmond) and Mrs. William Osborn (Alice) 1908 ff. (Box 377)
      - Pope, Bayard 1932-1966 (Box 377)
      - Purdy, Lawson, C.O.S. Secretary and Director 1918-39; Com. on Housing 1917-38 (Box 377)
      - Randall, Ollie A. (Box 377)
      - Rockefeller, John D., Ill and Mrs. Blanchette Hooker R. 1931 - also see Rockefellers in Foundations and in Contributors (Box 377)
      - Roosevelt, Pres. Franklin D. and Mrs. 1929-54 (Box 377)
      - Saville, Thorndike (Box 377)
      - Scott, S. Spencer, 1950-56, Trustee and Chairman of Public Interest Com. (Box 377)
      - Schwarz, F.A.O. and Mrs. (duBois) 1937-52 (Box 377)
      - Sloan, George A., and Mrs. 1938-48, AICP and CSS Trustee (Box 377)
      - Stanley, Harold, and Mrs. (Box 377)
      - Statler Mrs. Ellsworth, 1936-58 (Box 377)
      - Streeter, Edward, 1931-58 (Box 377)
      - Thomas Andrew J. of Housing Com. and Architect of Early Housing Projects (Box 377)
      - Tousley, Clare M., Includes Autobiography, "Letter to Jeanie" (Box 377)
      - Warburg, Felix, 1907-1927 (Box 377)
      - White Harold T. and Mrs. Emily de Forest W. (Box 377)
    - Personnel: (Box 378)
      - General Staff Meetings, 1956-59 (Box 378)
      - Manuals (Box 378)
      - Personnel Practices Committee (Staff) 1939-49 (Box 378)
      - Personnel Practices Com. Minutes 1939-42; 1943-46; 1947-49 (Box 378)
      - Personnel Practices Com. Minutes 1950-54; 1955-59 (Box 379)
      - Personnel Practices, Conference Group on Minutes and Memos 1941-43 (Box 379)
      - Recruitment of Puerto Rican Social Workers, 1950-63 (Box 379)
      - Staff Lists 1939-54 (Box 379)
      - Staff Participation 1955-56 (Box 379)
      - Union Organization Effort 1946 (Box 379)
    - Policies and Procedures, Miscellaneous (Box 379)
    - Private Schools Project, 1934-40 (Box 379)
    - Professional Conference (in Family Services) 1958 Vols. I, II, III, IV (Proceedings) (Box 380)
    - Psychiatric Consultants in Family Services, 1950-55 (Box 380)
    - Public Affairs Bureau, then Department:
      - Program and Purpose, 1946-60 (Box 380)
      - Bureau Self-Study 1959 (for Board Study of CSS) (Box 380)
      - Study of Court Structure, Court Reorganization, 1952-61 (Box 380)
      - Housing, see Housing (Box 380)
      - Interdepartmental Committee (Staff) Minutes 1949-51 (Box 380)
      - Maternity Service Project, see Health (Box 381)
      - Miscellaneous 1950 ff. (Box 381)
      - Report of 1959-60 (Box 381)
      - Public Welfare 1959-60 (Box 381)
      - Residency Requirements for Public Welfare (Box 381)
    - Public Funds, Use of, see Purchase of Service (Box 381)
    - Public Interest Committee 12/49 to 6/58 Minutes (Box 381)
    - Department 1940-60 (Box 381)
    - Purchase of Service: Use of Public Funds by Voluntary Agency (Box 381)
    - Queens Borough Office of CSS (Box 381)
    - Annexation of Family Welfare Society of Queens by COS in 1937 (Box 381)
    - History of Borough Office to 1948 (Box 381)
    - Relief - Miscellaneous, 1889 ff.
      - Practice, Study of, and Philosophy by Gramercy and Gorlears District Staffs 1939 (Box 381)
      - Study Conference 1941 (Box 382)
      - Conference Discussion, 1941 (Box 382)
    - Reorganization 1949-54: Change in Structure Recommended by 100th Anniversary Survey Committee 1949 and ff. (Box 382)
    - 1951-1952 - Closed until 2000 see Box 424 (Box 382)
    - 1960 see Study of CSS "Searchlight on New York" (Box 382)
    - Research see also Studies, internal:
      - Annual Reports of Institute of Welfare Research 1950 - 61; Summaries 1941-42 1939-40 (Box 382)
      - Formation of Institute of Welfare Research 1939-41 (Box 383)
      - Institute of Welfare Research Miscellaneous I 1942 - 51; Miscellaneous II (Box 383)
      - Joint Research Com 1953-60, Minutes (Box 383)
      - Studies: Components of Movement (in Casework) Includes Proposal and Planning; also see in Reports Section (Box 383)
      - Studies: Diagnostic Study on Child Observations in Queens District 1942 (Box 384)
      - Studies: Electrical Recording of Interviews with Clients 1950, 1955 (Box 384)
      - Studies: "Family Relations in Sickness and Health" with Cornell U. Medical College 1939-43, to be published as "Patients Have Families" by Commonwealth Fund (Box 384)
      - Studies: Measuring Movement in Casework 1942-48; also see in Reports Section (Box 384)
      - The Short-Term Case in a Family Agency 1953-57 (Box 384)
      - Young Family Project, Proposed 1954-55 (Box 384)
    - Residency Laws for Public Assistance Clients (Box 384)
    - Rikers Island Project 1957-59: Proposed Casework Service to (Box 384)
    - Families of Inmates (Box 384)
    - Social Work Recruiting Committee (Box 385)
    - Minutes 1956-58 (Box 385)
    - Miscellaneous 1954-59 (Box 385)
    - Social Service Exchange 1882 (C.O.S.) - 1963 (Misfiled? Not Found 7/81) (Box 385)
    - Speeches and Papers:
      - Burritt, Bailey B. (Box 385)
      - Davies, Stanley P. (Box 385)
      - Guests (Box 385)
      - Board and Staff, Miscellaneous Vols. I, II, II, IV (Box 386)
      - At Interdepartmental Meetings (Box 386)
    - Staten Island, Questions of Merging with S.I. Family Agency, 1940-59 (Box 386)
    - Statistics (Box 386)
    - Financial (Box 386)
    - Financial and Service, Monthly Charts 1948-52 (Box 386)
    - Financial and Service, Monthly Charts 1943-47; 1940-42 (Box 387)
    - Statistics - Service
      - Analysis of Family Service Statistics 1939-42 (Box 387)
      - Casework Statistics Subcommittee on, 1953 (Box 387)
      - Handbook for Caseworkers: Family Service Statistics, 1950 Handbook for Office Assistant: Family Service Statistics 1950 (Box 387)
      - Total Family Service Statistics 1938-39 to 1959-60 (14 Folders) 1938-1942 (Box 387)
      - Total Family Service Statistics 1942-1951 (Box 388)
      - Total Family Service Statistics 1951-1960 (Box 389)
    - Studies, Internal: Self Studies of the Society's Function, re: Future Program
      - Family Services 1959 see in Studies: Searchlight (Box 389)
      - Family Services Time-Cost Study 1957 (Casework) (Box 389)
      - Family Services Time-Cost Study 1957 (PHN Section) (Box 389)
    - Studies, Internal (Box 390)
      - Institute of Welfare Research Self Study 1959 (Box 390)
      - Plan and Scope Committee of the Board, Miscellaneous, 1949-55 (Box 390)
      - Plan and Scope Com. Study of CSS Committees 1951 (Box 390)
      - Plan and Scope Com. Consultant Plan (Nurses and Caseworkers) (Box 390)
      - Plan and Scope Com. Educational Nursing Department, Folders I & II, 1949-51 (Box 390)
      - Plan and Scope Com. Institute of Welfare Research, 1950-51 (Box 391)
      - Plan and Scope Com. Record Books I and II 1949-52 (Box 391)
      - Proposed Future Program for CSS by Alice D. Taggart, 1958 (Box 391)
      - "Searchlight on New York11, I960; Board Action and Costs (Box 391)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Family Services 1959 (Box 391)
      - "Searchlight on New York", Interviews 1959 Folders I and II (Box 391)